# Jascha Ephraim

54 Rose Ave, Apt 8
Venice, CA 90291
202-470-6098
jaschaephraim@gmail.com
https://github.com/jaschaephraim
http://jaschaephraim.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am currently a full-stack software engineer at Cargomatic Inc., and have been a freelance developer since 2005. I have professional experience with a variety of frontend and backend technologies, and enjoy adapting quickly to new ones.

While most of my professional experience is in web development, I particularly enjoy working on projects involving machine learning, artificial neural networks, simulations, etc. I would love to branch into game development at some point in my career.

My work is informed by multiple aptitudes and life experiences, including musical composition and performance, multimedia production, writing and editing, and Buddhist chaplaincy.

#### **PROFICIENCIES**

- · Backend: Go, Node.js, Python, PHP, Ruby, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Neo4J
- Frontend: JavaScript/ES6, CoffeeScript, Webpack, React, Redux, CSS3, HTML5
- · Devops: Sysadmin, AWS, Docker
- Scientific applications: Java, Matlab, R, E-Prime

#### NOTABLE PROJECTS

- <u>Emergency Market Mapping and Analysis Tool</u> developed for the International Rescue Committee and USAID. Browser-based, offline graphical mapping tool utilizing ES6, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Cytoscape.js, Webpack.
- <u>Bayesian decision network modeler and evaluator</u> written in Java, implementing both absolute probability calculation and estimation via Gibbs sampling.
- Static website generator and development environment written in Node.is.
- <u>LiveReload server for Go.</u>
- Article on <u>Elementary Neural Networks with TensorFlow: Training Perceptrons to Do Boolean Logic</u>.

#### **EDUCATION**

2012–2015	University of the West Rosemead, CA M.Div., Buddhist Chaplaincy
2010–2011	University of California Merced, CA B.S., Cognitive Science High Honors, Dean's List, Chancellor's List
2009–2010	City College of San Francisco San Francisco, CA
2003-2004	${\bf University\ of\ North\ Carolina\ } \textit{Asheville,\ NC}$
2000-2003	Warren Wilson College Swannanoa, NC

### RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### 2016-present Software Engineer

### Cargomatic

Full-stack development—specializing in backend—of scalable shipping platform, including web and mobile clients, real-time location tracking, billing, operations administration, exception ticketing and resolution. Built using Node.js, Go, React, AWS.

### 1995–2015 Freelance Web Developer

Provided web design and development services, adapting open-source content management systems and creating custom frameworks.

#### 2010–2011 Research Assistant

### Laboratory of Professor Michael Spivey, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Assisted in design and implementation of behavioral experiments, ran subjects, maintained detailed records. Experiments involved mouse tracking, eye tracking, timed visual search.

#### Research Programmer

## Laboratory of Professor Evan Heit, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Programmed experiments according to specifications using Java and E-Prime. Studies addressed judgements involving deduction, induction, and varying reliability of information sources.

#### Web Developer/Graphic Designer/Proofreader

### Laboratory of Professor Qinghua Guo, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Designed lab and departmental websites, design and layout of print materials, proofreading of scientific journal submissions. Articles addressed spatial analysis of environmental LIDAR data.